Jordan Willian Marques Pereira

Computer Engineer

Website: https://jordanwmp.github.io

Whatsapp: +55 (98) 9 8718-0471

Email: jordan.marques@discente.ufma.br

Location: Rosário, MA, Brazil - Available for national/international relocation.

Professional Profile

I have a degree in Computer Engineering and I intend to build a solid career as a Software Engineer and Architect, with an emphasis on Front-End and Mobile development, through hybrid technologies. My work is focused on the JavaScript ecosystem, exploring its versatility for the development of APIs, mobile applications and web platforms.

I seek to integrate the theoretical foundations of computing with practical challenges, maintaining a continuous learning routine, through studies, reading and specialized courses, constantly improving my skills as a Computer Engineer.

Professional Experience

Noby Academy | Freelancer | 2023 - 2024

 Engineered a sales enhancement app featuring Al-driven video generation based on user prompts and integrated analytics for data-informed decision-making.

Presidente Dutra University Hospital | Internship | 2023 - 2023

 Developed a blood bag management system to streamline inventory and reduce unnecessary requests caused by manual handling.

Exact Engineering | Freelancer | Mobile | 2022

 Developed a mobile app to automate occupational safety engineering reports, with offline support, reducing report preparation time, lowering paper-related costs, and centralizing company data. Sousândrade Foundation | Scientific Research | 2020 - 2021

• I developed a physical-chemical monitoring system to support public-private

field data collection, facilitating data analysis for researchers.

Adsum | Software Engineering | 2019 - 2020

Led project management, requirements analysis, and software development

in a tech startup, overseeing task delegation, deadline planning, and client

deliverables.

Adsum | Internship | 2018 - 2019

Contributed to the development of a web-based machinery management

platform for a logistics port company, focusing on the reporting module for

equipment data analysis and export.

Academic Background:

Bachelor of Computer Engineering, Federal University of Maranhão, October

3. 2024

Technical Skills

Algorithms, Software Engineering, Software Architecture, Scrum, Javascript,

Typescript, Angular, Vue.js, React, React Native, Expo, Ionic Framework, Capacitor,

Node.js, API, Sequelize, Prisma, RxJS, Redux, Redux Toolkit, Pinia, Jest, Jasmine,

Webpack, PWA, Git, HTML, CSS, Tailwind, SASS, Bootstrap, Angular Material,

Firebase, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, Redis, Play Console, Google Cloud,

Trello, Google Admob, RevenueCat, Gather Town, Java, C, Python, PHP.

Languages

Portuguese: Native

English: Intermediate

Russian: Beginner

Complementary Activities

• I participated in digital transformation projects at the Federal University of

Maranhão

- I developed a desktop system for managing servers with health complications at the Federal University of Maranhão
- I taught a Data Science course at National Oceanography Week for Physical Oceanography.